Hey, in the last video I told you that
you can put functions into variables. So
let's look at what that would look like.
So let's create a function. Um,
and we'll just call this function add
two numbers. And we'll take in a num one
and a num two. We'll do some work. Um,
we'll say let results equal num one plus
num two. And then we'll give some
output. So we'll return num one plus num
two. Okay,
or sorry we'll return the result.
There's no point in doing the work
twice. So this entire thing could be
simplified to just saying return num one
plus num two. But I like to have it
split onto two lines because it makes
you easier to it makes it easier to show
things in the debugger. So we've created
a function. It takes two pieces of
input. It does some work and then it
gives some output. Now let's create a
variable. Um we'll create a variable
called my var. And we'll set it equal to
um a string. Hello. Okay. So that's how
you set a variable equal to a string.
Um let's create another variable um and
set it equal to a number. And that's how
you set it equal to a number. Let's
create another variable and let's set it
equal to a boolean. Um
okay. Well, now I'm going to create
another variable and say let my
function equal. Then I'm going to say
set it equal to add two numbers.
Okay, notice something different about
the syntax. If I wanted the result of
adding the two numbers, then I could say
let result equal add two numbers one and
two.
Notice I put parenthesis. When I put
parenthesis, I'm saying run the
function. Give me the result. Here I'm
saying don't run the function, just set
my variable equal to that function.
So that means that on this line I could
say um let result two equal
my function and call it and give it um
two and three. Okay, let's save this and
let's just go see this in action. So
let's go live. Okay, we're going to
inspect the page
and let's put a break point on line 15.
Okay, we'll reload our page. So, we're
about to create a variable called hello.
Cool. We've created the variable. If we
hover over my var, it stores hello.
Um, we've created our others. If we look
at my num, it stores 10. If we look at
my bool, it stores true. So, we're about
to set my function equal to add two
numbers. Add two numbers. If you hover
over it, it says that's a function that
does uh that takes two inputs, does some
work, and gives some output. If we hit
next now, if we hover over my function,
it says that's a function that takes two
pieces of input, does some work, and
gives some output. Now, we're going to
call the function. So, we're saying let
result equal add two numbers, one and
two. So, if we hit next, it jumps up to
add two numbers. Num one is the one we
passed in. Num two is the two we passed
in. If we add those together, we get
three. So, if we hover over result, we
get three. And we're about to return
three back to the program.
and we return it back to the program.
Result is now three. Now we're about to
call result two and we're setting it
equal to my function. Well, what is my
function? My function is a variable. And
what is it storing? It's storing the
function called add two numbers. So,
we're about to jump up to that function.
So, we'll hit next and we jump up to
that function. Num one is the two that
we passed in. Num two is the three that
we passed in. And so now we can take
those two numbers together, add them,
the result is five, and we can return
them to the main program. And now if we
hover over result two, we can see the
result is five. So why is this
important? And why did I take the time
to show you this? Why didn't I just call
my function my function in the first
place if I was just going to rename it a
few lines later? Well, what I'm trying
to show you is that a variable can hold
a function. And if a variable can hold a
function, it lets us do some pretty cool